Guide to the Stewart Brand Papers M1237
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stewart Brand papers
1954-2000
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Brand, Stewart
M1237
53 Linear Feet (120 manuscript boxes, 4 flat boxes, 17 seven-inch reels, 15 audiocassettes, 140 micro-cassettes, 3 hard disk cartridges)
The Steward Brand papers contains correspondence, personal journals, manuscripts, photographs, project records, articles, and publications.
Biographical / Historical
Writer, editor, entrepreneur, and futurist Stewart Brand was born December 14, 1938 in Rockford, Illinois. He attended Phillips Exeter Academy in New Hampshire, and attended Stanford University where he studied biology with Paul Ehrlich. After graduating he joined the U.S. Army and was trained as a parachutist and later photographer. He studied design at the San Francisco Art Institute and photography at San Francisco State. In 1962, Brand took his first LSD trip in 1962 under the guidance of James Fadiman at the International Foundation for Advanced Study in Menlo Park. In the mid-60s Brand co-produced the Trips Festival as well as other happenings such as America Needs Indians. He was loosely associated with the Merry Pranksters, USCO, and other countercultural groups, and spent much of the 1960s traveling and visiting communal experiments.
Brand created the original Whole Earth Catalog in 1968 to provide practical information on tools that would be useful for people creating and living in communes. The Catalog went on to gain wide popularity. In 1972 he also co-founded the Point Foundation, the non-profit organization that runs all Whole Earth activities. Between 1974-1985, Brand founded, edited, and published CoEvolution Quarterly, which continued as the Whole Earth Review (1985), then later as the Whole Earth Magazine. Brand was also the editor-in-chief of the short-lived Whole Earth Software Catalog, and in 1984 he organized the first Hacker's Conference in Marin County. The following year, Brand and Larry Brilliant founded The WELL ("Whole Earth 'Lectronic Link"), a prototypical online community inspired by Douglas Engelbart's Augmentation work; Brand had been a camera operator for "The Mother of All Demos" in 1968.
After getting involved with MIT's Media Lab and organizing strategic planning conferences for various corporations, Brand was one of the founders of the business consulting firm Global Business Network. GBN's parent company the Monitor Group was acquired by Deloitte in 2013. Brand's most recent venture has been with the Long Now Foundation, which promotes long-term thinking through a number of projects including the construction of a millenial clock.
His books include The Clock Of The Long Now (1999), How Buildings Learn: What Happens After They're Built (1994) and The Media Lab: Inventing the Future at MIT (1987). In Two Cybernetic Frontiers (1974), which focused on Gregory Bateson and cutting-edge computer science, he coined the term "personal computer." His most recent book is 2009's Whole Earth Discipline: An Ecopragmatist Manifesto.
Scope and Contents
The Stewart Brand papers are arranged in the following order:
Series I, Boxes 1-16: Correspondence, 1954-1994
Series II, Boxes 17-22: Personal notebooks, datebooks, address books, 1955-1999
Series III, Boxes 23-29: Biographical, 1952-1997; Series IV, Boxes 30-107: Projects, 1967-2000
Series V, Boxes 108-116: Miscellaneous (includes newspaper/magazine articles)
Series VI, Boxes 117-119: Media
Series VII, Boxes 120-124: Business records, 1962-1993 ((RESTRICTED)
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research, with the exception of Series VII: Business Records, which are closed until Brand's death. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy. Selected audiovisual material has been transferred and is available digitally.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stewart Brand, 2001. Accessions 2001-163, 2017-252, 2017-331, and 2017-332.
Related Materials
Stanford Special Collections holds many collections related to Brand, including the following:
Interview with Stewart Brand in Bucky Conversations: Conversations on the Life and Work of an Enigmatic Genius, 2002-2003 (M1915) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/fr963yt9378
Gerd Stern papers (M1954) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10176361
Zach Stewart papers, 1964-1974 (M2206) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/11953459
Whole Earth Catalog records, 1969-1986 (M1045) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4320145
Point foundation records, 1964-1975 (M1441) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/5704614
Global Business Network records, circa 1988-2012 (M1958) Closed until processed
Fred Turner papers, 1968-2011 (SC1146) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10287606
Moss, Rose; How Buildings Learn; Kesey, Ken; Santa Fe Institute (Santa Fe, N.M.); Coevolution Quarterly; Whole Earth 'Lectronic Link; Engelbart, D. C., 1925-2013; Brando, Marlon; Brand, Stewart; Whole Earth Catalog; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster); Brand, Stewart; Sausalito (Calif.); Western Behavioral Sciences Institute; Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Media Laboratory; Learning Conference; Global Business Network; Long Now Foundation; Point (Foundation)
- Series I: Correspondence
  Scope and Contents
  Materials have been arranged chronologically according to year; although, due to the large number of correspondences, materials have not been arranged chronologically by month and day. Also, the materials have not been refoldered unless necessary.
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (undated) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (with photographs) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: no date (with enclosure) [ca. 1959?] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: no date [ca. 1958-1959] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1960 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1961, January (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1961, February (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1961, March (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1961, April (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1961, May (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1961, June (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1961, July (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1961, August (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1961, August (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1961, September (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1961, October (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 1961, November (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: 1961, December (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1961, December (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1962, January (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1962, February (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1962, March (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1962, April (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1962, May (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1962, June (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1962, July (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1962, August (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1962, September (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1962, October (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1962, November (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 1962, December (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: 1963, January (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1963, February (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1963, March (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1963, April (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1963, May (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1963, June (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1963, July (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1963, August (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1963, September (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1963, October (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1963, November (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: 1963, December (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: 1964, January (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: 1964, February (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: 1964, March (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: 1964, April (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: 1964, May (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: 1964, November-December (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: 1965 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: 1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to Julie Brand: 1967-1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1968-1970 [w/ Whole Earth Catalog correspondence] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1969 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1970 [with Whole Earth Catalog corr.] (Box 6a, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1970 [with Whole Earth Catalog corr.] (Box 6a, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1971 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1971 (Box 6a, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1978 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Brand/Carol [Van Strum] correspondence: 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Brand/Carol [Van Strum] correspondence: 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: 1979 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: 1980 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: 1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1987 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1988 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1988 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1989 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: 1992 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: 1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1993 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: 1994 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: 1994 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Next Whole Earth Catalog, ca. 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Planetree, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Penguin and Random, 1974-1979 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - CoEvolution Quarterly: Business miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - CoEvolution Quarterly: Business miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - CoEvolution Quarterly: Business miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Uncommon Courtesy: Business miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Uncommon Courtesy: Business miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Uncommon Courtesy: Business miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1988 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Series II: Notebooks/Datebooks/Address books
  - Notebooks: 1955-1956 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: 1957 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: 1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: 1957-1959 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: July, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: 1960-1962 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: 1962-1963 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks: 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks: Summer 1964 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Notebooks: 1964-1965 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Notebooks: 1966-1969 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Notebooks: 1969-1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: June - August 1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: miscellaneous notes, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: February 1973 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: February 1977 - August 1978 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: August 1978 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks: 1982 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks: May 1985 - November 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: November 1985 - September 1986 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks: 1985 - 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: September 1986 - October 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: 1987 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: February 1988 - June 1988 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: June 1988 - January 1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks: February 1989 - July 1989 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks: July 1989 - December 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks: October 16-17, 23-24 n.y. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Memo-book/notebook, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks: no date (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: no date (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: no date, "Notions" (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: no date, "Quotes" (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Monthly datebooks, ca. 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Datebooks, 1976-1978 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Datebooks, 1984-1988 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Datebooks, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Address book, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Datebooks, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Datebooks, 1991-1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Datebooks, 1993-1994 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Datebooks, 1995-1996 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Datebooks, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Datebooks, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Datebooks, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Address book, no date (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Address book, no date (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Series III: Biographical
  Biographical material consists largely of early writings in high school and at Stanford University. However, there are materials related to his military career, his time as a photographer, and his tenure at Whole Earth. Also included are ephemeral items from his early childhood.
  - High School notebooks, 1952-1958 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - High School notebooks, 1952-1958 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - High School History class: papers and notes, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - High School History class: papers and notes, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - High School History class: papers and notes, 1955-1956 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - History 5, 1956 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Paper: "Flying Tigers," 1956 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook: "Keith Review," 1952 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook: "The Warrior," 1953 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook: "The Warrior," 1954 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook: "The Pean," 1955 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Exeter High School diploma, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Stanford University transcript, 1956-1960 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Sloan Scholarship appointment, Stanford University, 1957 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Stanford University diploma, 1960 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Research material regarding Wildlife Refuge controversy, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, ca. 1955-1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, 1956-1957 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, 1956-1958 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, 1957-1959 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays: "Take it Out on Clay," 1959 [with photographs] (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Writings/essays: Jasper Ridge Tarantulas, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Writings/essays: "Intersex: Our Snickering Ignorance," 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Notes regarding article on Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioural Sciences, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Notes regarding article on Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioural Sciences, 1959-1960 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Writings/essays: "The Several Bohemians," 1960 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, ca. 1960 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Writings/essays: "Fruits of a Scholar's Paradise," ca. 1960 [with photographs] (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, ca. 1961 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays: "Wolfa," n.d. [with photographs] (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous writings/essays, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - "The Meaning," authur unknown [possibly Brand], n.d. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - "Textures of Life," n.d. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - ROTC, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous photographic publications, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - National Book Award, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Who's Who certificates, 1976/1977, 1982/1983 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Exeter class of 1956, newsletter: 1999 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - High school/Stanford University photographs, 1950's (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Whole Earth staff photographs (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Whole Earth Catalog: negatives of staff, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, ca. early 1970's (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Photographic negative: National Book Award, ca. 1972 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Portrait series, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Last will and testament of Ralph C. Morley (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera: conservation pledge; passport; miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Stewart Brand photographs: framed (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Brand ephemera: child boxing gloves, ROTC medal, political pins, rubber stamps (Box 29)
- Series IV: Projects
  Stewart Brand's involvement with various organizations and projects constitute the bulk of this collection. While every attempt to arrange materials by project has been made, there is certainly overlap, and thus some files on one project may have been inadvertenly filed under a different project.
  - Native American Indian Research, 1967- (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - War God, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - La Luz gathering, March 1969 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Statement to the Select Subcommittee on Education, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - "Indians and Counter Culture," research and publication, 1971-1973 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Soft Technology, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - The Complete Works of Gregory Bateson, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Bateson manuscript, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Bateson photograph (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Both Sides of the Necessary Paradox" (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - POINT, correspondence/minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - POINT, correspondence/minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - POINT, correspondence/minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - POINT, correspondence/minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Gregroy Bateson material, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Bateson article, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Gregory Bateson, 1975-1977 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Gregory Bateson: slides, April 1978 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Gregory Bateson: 1978-1980 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Gregory Bateson: 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Gregory Bateson: 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1982 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1983 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, "Spacewar," draft [ca. 1970-1972] (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, etc.: 1973-1975 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, etc.: 1973-1975 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, etc.: 1972-1983 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, etc.: 1972-1983 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, etc.: 1972-1983 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Stockholm Conference, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Stockholm Conference, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Cybernetic Frontiers, 1972-1973 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Cybernetic Frontiers photographs, 1972-1973 (Spacewar) (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Marlon Brando script/interview, ca. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Marlon Brando script/interview, ca. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Marlon Brando script/interview, ca. 1975 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Whole Earth film/television contracts [1981?] (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Space Exploration, 1975-1979 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Space Exploration, 1978-1982 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Space Exploration, 1980-1982 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Space Exploration, 1980-1982 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Space Travel manuscript, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Space photographs (space shuttle, etc.) (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Space exploration: publications (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - New Games expeditions, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Governor's conference on Holistic health, 1976-1977 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Brown-Buckley-Kerr debate, ca. 1975-1976 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Mind/Body conference, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Mind/Body conference, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Mind/Body conference, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1980 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1980 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Metric debate, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Metric debate, 1979-1983 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Metric debate: SB and CQ, meetings and notes (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Metric debate: "Good material" (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Metric debate: personal and work experience (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Metric debate: miscellaneous correspondence (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Metric debate: arguments, anti (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Metric debate: anti-metric articles and published letters (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Metric debate: pro-metric articles and published letters (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Metric debate: periodicals (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Metric debate: miscellaneous articles (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Metric debate: Americans for customary weights and measure (Box 41, Folder 5)